<tool id="interactomix_bips" name="BIPS" version="0.1">
	<description>
	</description>
	<command>/usr/bin/python /interactomix/bin-tools/BIPS/execute_bips_wrapper.py -i '$in' -it '$in_type' -tax '$tax_id' -ot '$out_type' -out '$out'</command>
	<inputs>
		<param name="in" type="data" label="Input File"/>
		<param name="in_type" type="select" label="Input Type">
			<option value="fasta_file">Fasta File</option>
			<option value="uniprotentry">Uniprot Entry</option>
			<option value="uniprotaccession">Uniprot Accession</option>
			<option value="genesymbol">Gene Symbol</option>
		</param>
		<param name="tax_id" type="text" label="Tax ID"/>
		<param name="out_type" type="select" label="Output Type">
			<option value="uniprotentry">Uniprot Entry</option>
			<option value="uniprotaccession">Uniprot Accession</option>
			<option value="genesymbol">Gene Symbol</option>
		</param>
	</inputs>
	<outputs>
		<data name="out"/>
	</outputs>
	<help><![CDATA[
Introduction
^^^^^^^^^^^^
The hyopthesis used by BIPS is that two proteins (A and B) interact if there
exists a known interaction between two proteins (A' and B') such that A is
similar to A' and B is similar to B'.  The known interactions between A' and
B' is called the *template interaction*. In BIPS, protein A is the *user query
protein* and protein B is the *predicted target protein*.  The basis of the hypothesis
is to assume the similar behavior of homolog proteins.  The approach uses sequence
similarity between proteins based on the sequence alignment.  We align the sequences
of two proteins to measure their similarity as a function of the percentage of
identical residues and the percentage of their sequence being aligned (for example
using 60% identity and 70% of the total length of the target protein and 90%
of the template).  Template sequence coverage is always fixed to 90%.

In a second approach we measure the similarity of the target sequences (A and B)
with PFAM domains as a function of the e-value calculated with the package.  This
results in the assignation of one or several PFAM domains to the query and target
sequences.  Then, we use the database of iPfam and 3DiD to check for domain-domain
interactions.  We hypothesize that A interacts with B if a domain A' can be assigned
to A and a domain B' to B such that A' and B' are interacting domains in iPfam or
3DiD.  Furhermore, it has been shown that the specificity of some interactions depends
on a set of interacting domains.  Therefore, the most restrictive set of predictions will be those
for which both criteria of similarity are required,  using stringent values of
sequence identity, coverage and domain assignation.

Inputs
^^^^^^
Input is a single file containing the query proteins.  This file is either a fasta
file containing their sequences, or a file containing standard protein identifiers.
The type of the file must be specified in the input type parameter.

It is also possible to limit the predictions to those of a particular species as
well as specify the type of the output.

Output
^^^^^^
The output is a single file containing a list of protein identifiers of the type
specified.  These proteins are the predicted target proteins.

	]]></help>
</tool>
