<tool id="interactomix_iloops" name="ILoops" version="0.1">
	<description>
	</description>
	<command interpreter="sh">
		./iloops.sh $fasta $query $grouping $domain $cost $out_xml
	</command>
	<environment_variables>
		<environment_variable name="TERM">linux</environment_variable>
	</environment_variables>
	<inputs>
		<param name="fasta" type="data" format="fasta" label="Fasta Sequences"/>
		<param name="query" type="data" label="Query Protein Pair"/>
		<param name="grouping" type="select" label="Grouping">
			<option value="lg">lg</option>
			<option value="lgd">lgd</option>
			<option value="dg">dg</option>
			<option value="all">all</option>
		</param>
		<param name="domain" type="select" label="Domain Type">
			<option value="SCOP">SCOP</option>
			<option value="PFAM">PFAM</option>
			<option value="CATH">CATH</option>
		</param>
		<param name="cost" type="select" label="Cost">
			<option value="1">1</option>
			<option value="5">5</option>
			<option value="6">6</option>
			<option value="7">7</option>
			<option value="8">8</option>
			<option value="9">9</option>
			<option value="10">10</option>
			<option value="11">11</option>
			<option value="12">12</option>
			<option value="13">13</option>
			<option value="14">14</option>
			<option value="15">15</option>
			<option value="20">20</option>
			<option value="30">30</option>
			<option value="40">40</option>
			<option value="50">50</option>
		</param>
	</inputs>
	<outputs>
		<data name="out_xml" format="xml"/>
	</outputs>
<help><![CDATA[
Introduction
^^^^^^^^^^^^
Protein-protein interaction (PPI) has been described as one of the main
processes by which proteins perform their cellular functions. Thus, correctly
identifying the PPI network (or protein interactome) of a given organism would
be useful both to understand the key molecular mechanisms behind a biological
function and to assign a function to an unknown protein based on its
interactions. The iLoops Server uses the loop classification as defined
in `ArchDB <http://sbi.imim.es/archdb/>`_ and/or the `SCOP <http://scop.mrc-lmb.cam.ac.uk/scop/>`_
classification of domains to predict whether or not
a pair of proteins interact. The method uses data from both known interactions
and putative no-interactions (NIPs) identified as co-localized, non-redundant,
non-interacting random pairs of proteins non-similar to PPIs to define
interacting (positive) or non-interacting (negative) relations between
groups of similar structural features of different proteins. Several
parameters extracted from the positive and negative interaction signatures
(the ratio of the number of signatures or the ratio of their top p-value
among them) are submitted to a random forest analysis to describe if there
is or not an interaction.

Inputs
^^^^^^
Sequences
---------
A fasta file containing a set of sequences.  The first word of the header line
of each sequence is used as the identifier code for that protein.

Interactions
------------
This file contains a list of protein pairs.  Each line is a protein identifier
code (see above) followed by a double colon (::), followed by another protein
identifier code.  For instance: protein1::protein2.

Grouping
--------
TODO 

Domain Type
-----------
The domain to be mapped on the given sequences.

Cost
----
This is the relative cost of false predictions, in reference to the random
forest classifier.  Increasing this value will improve the positive prediction
value of the prediction, but will tend to decrease the true positive rate.

	]]></help>
</tool>
